<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Justin Hong</title>
    <description>Welcome! I’m Justin Hong, a Los Angeles-based software engineer.  This is my programming-related website.
</description>
    <link>https://abigsmall.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://abigsmall.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 23:33:26 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 23:33:26 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Podcasts and Productivity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been listening to podcasts for a while now, but it’s only been in the past several years in which I’ve increasingly noticed a disturbing correlation involving them in my life. Namely, days I listen to podcasts are days I get less done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only have anecdotal evidence and my intuition to back me on this, but even as I think it’s true it also makes me sad: I like listening to podcasts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony of it all is that a big reason for my gravitation towards the medium was the perceived productivity benefit. I could wash the dishes and learn about history or be driving and get up to date on the latest Apple punditry. It never got to the point of listening to podcasts while showering, but if I had a portable speaker lying around I’m sure I would’ve scrub-a-dub-dubbed to John Siracusa belaboring the finer points of his TiVo hierarchy of needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days I’m trying to allow more time to be bored and be alone with my thoughts, and doggone it if I’m not getting more done. Podcasts are more of a special treat now, which in turn makes me way more selective in which episode to pick. Come to think of it, not a bad way to live life overall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 23:29:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://abigsmall.github.io/2016/02/19/podcasts-and-productivity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://abigsmall.github.io/2016/02/19/podcasts-and-productivity.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things that have tripped me up while writing JavaScript</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Some common mistakes I’ve made that could’ve been relatively easily avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these would probably not be a problem if I changed the settings in the text editor that I use. Actually, a better blog post than this one would be highlighting useful text editor settings/plug-ins. But I have a deadline so ¯\_(ツ)_/¯.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-saving-your-files&quot;&gt;Not saving your files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You make some changes to your code, refresh your browser or run the code in your terminal or wherever, and then… nothing. Nothing changes. ?!?!? You look over your code again, furiously, scanning over each line, character by character. After having looked over your code for the umpteenth time, all you’re left with is a satisfaction at your code’s pristine logic and an intense bewilderment at why your code’s beauty is not being represented in the real world. After several minutes of this, you realize that you didn’t save your changes. Yeah, so save your changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forgetting-a-return-statement&quot;&gt;Forgetting a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;return&lt;/code&gt; statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Console doesn’t show any errors and yet I don’t see what I expect. Could be a case of simply forgetting a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;return&lt;/code&gt; statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say the below code is in a function, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;anotherFunction&lt;/code&gt; is a function that returns something. To be more specific, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;anotherFunction&lt;/code&gt; is a pure function that returns a value and doesn’t have a side effect. That is, the entire purpose of using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;anotherFunction&lt;/code&gt; is to return the value that it returns:
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
if (something) {
   anotherFunction();
 }
&lt;/code&gt;
Yet we forgot to return &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;anotherFunction&lt;/code&gt;’s value!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
if (something) {
  return anotherFunction();
}
&lt;/code&gt;
Ahh, much better. I’m not sure if linters can check for this. It would do me some good to do some research. I’ll do some later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 09:06:46 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://abigsmall.github.io/javascript/2015/09/17/things-that-have-tripped-me-up-while-writing-javascript.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://abigsmall.github.io/javascript/2015/09/17/things-that-have-tripped-me-up-while-writing-javascript.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
